# **AMANAT JAISINGHANI**

amanatjaisinghani@gmail.com | (416) 832-3356 https://amanatjaisinghani.github.io/Amanat-Jaisinghani-Interactive-Resume/

## **PROFILE**

An analytical organized professional with over ten years of hospitality and management experience. Enterprising and ambitious, with a positive, approachable attitude, and a thirst for learning. Resilient problem solver who is adaptable when challenges and opportunities arise. Excellent at account management and client retention. Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, and Bootstrap.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## 2013 - 2021 Sales Manager | Hilton Toronto

- Accelerated sales by exceeding targets.
  - Recipient of Hilton's Circle of Excellence 2019. Achieved 143% of 2019 annual target of \$1.5M.
  - Achieved 118% of 2018 annual target of \$1.2M and 103% of 2017 annual target of \$1M.
  - Enhanced the site visit experience in 2019 with a conversion rate of 98%.
- Solicited new accounts through targeted sales efforts and by shifting market share.
- Conducted market analysis to build budgets and manage forecasts to maximize revenue.
- Executed marketing tactics by creating content, based on industry trends that generated new revenue streams and deliver a high return on investment.
- Engaged in multiple task force opportunities in various markets and cities.

## 2018 – 2021 President | CHMSE (Canadian Hotel Marketing & Sales Executives)

- Oversaw the activities of the Board of Directors including the Executive team.
- Chair Board of Directors meetings including setting agendas.

## 2010 – 2013 Duty Manager | Residence Inn by Marriott Downtown Toronto

- Supervised front office associates and encouraged their development.
- Strategized ways to maximize revenue by accelerating occupancy, boosting Average Daily Rate and Revenue Per Available Room
- Audited the guest ledger by balancing revenue, resolving discrepancies, and producing daily reports.
- Administered schedules and payroll, prepared invoices, and assisted with accounts receivables.

## **EDUCATION**

## 2010 - 2012 George Brown College | Toronto, Ontario

Bachelor of Applied Business (B.A.B.) in Hospitality Operations Management

## 2008 – 2010 George Brown College | Toronto, Ontario

Special Events Planning – Destination Tourism

# George Brown College | Toronto, Ontario

Centre for Hospitality and Culinary Arts - Program Advisory Committee Member